Before we get too deep into pre-train models,
let's look at the types of computer vision models there are.
We will mainly focus on classification,
detection, and segmentation here.
Now, there are other various types or sub-types here as well.
Pose estimation or text recognition,
for example, might not fit neatly into these categories.
Deep learning also has generation of content with GANs as well,
although that's not really applicable here.
First, let us look at classification.
Classification determines a given class that
an image or an object in an image belongs to.
This can scale from a simple yes/no answer such as hotdog versus
not hotdog up to potentially thousands of classes like a type of animal.
The ImageNet dataset often used to pre-train neural networks contains 20,000 classes.
The most well-known competition with ImageNet uses 1,000 of these classes,
90 of which are just for different dog breeds.
These usually have some probability by
class so that the highest probability is the determined class,
but you can also see the top five predictions, for example.
In detection, this gets used in
determining the objects appear at different places in an image.
At its most basic,
this could be similar to the yes/no classification of whether an object appears at all.
Typically, it's more advanced than this,
both detecting an object appears as well as where an image it appears.
Oftentimes, this will draw bounding boxes around
the detected objects so the output may be related to x,
y coordinates, as well as height and width of the object.
Usually, there's some form of classification built on,
depending on the network,
so that these bounding boxes also note which class they are.
These bounding boxes also have a confidence threshold,
so you can throw out low confidence predictions.
Next up is segmentation.
Segmentation classify sections of an image by classifying each and every pixel.
Once again, this can be simple,
like road versus not road or there may be tens of classes,
such as road, lay line,
grass, tree, sky, pedestrian.
You get it. Each and every pixel in the image will be put into a class,
although light classification, they may have different probabilities by pixel.
Now, these are often post-processed in some way to avoid phantom classes here and there.
There's also a subset of segmentation they consider,
semantic segmentation versus instance segmentation.
Semantic segmentation just focuses on classifying every pixel into a given class.
So two objects of the same class in an image are looked at the same.
On the other hand, instance segmentation actually
determines objects of the same class to be separate instances.
So two bikes could be separately tracked through a video.
We've looked at different types of computer vision models.
Now, let's look at some example architectures for computer vision models.